"use strict";(self.webpackChunkquiz_app=self.webpackChunkquiz_app||[]).push([[6008],{6008:e=>{e.exports=JSON.parse('[{"question":"What does AWS VPC stand for?","answers":[{"text":"Virtual Private Connection","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Virtual Private Cloud","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Virtual Private Cluster","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Virtual Private Communication","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"In which AWS service can you create and configure a VPC?","answers":[{"text":"Amazon RDS","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Amazon S3","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Amazon VPC","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Amazon DynamoDB","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the primary purpose of AWS VPC?","answers":[{"text":"To manage billing and cost allocation","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To provide scalable storage in the cloud","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To launch and operate virtual private servers","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To create a logically isolated section of the AWS Cloud where you can launch AWS resources","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"How many IP addresses can you associate with a single network interface in a VPC?","answers":[{"text":"One","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Five","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Ten","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Unlimited","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the maximum number of VPCs allowed per AWS region by default?","answers":[{"text":"5","isCorrect":false},{"text":"10","isCorrect":false},{"text":"50","isCorrect":false},{"text":"100","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Which component is used to connect a VPC to your corporate data center?","answers":[{"text":"Amazon VPC Gateway","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Amazon VPC Router","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Virtual Private Network (VPN)","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Amazon VPC Direct Connect","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is an Amazon VPC Security Group?","answers":[{"text":"A hardware device for encrypting traffic between VPCs","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A virtual router for managing VPC traffic","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A stateful firewall that controls inbound and outbound traffic to AWS resources","isCorrect":true},{"text":"A tool for optimizing VPC performance","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of an Amazon VPC subnet?","answers":[{"text":"To define user permissions within a VPC","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To segment the IP address range of a VPC","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To configure VPC peering connections","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To create a high-performance cache for VPC traffic","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the CIDR notation for the IP address range 192.168.0.0 to 192.168.255.255?","answers":[{"text":"192.168.0.0/16","isCorrect":true},{"text":"192.168.0.0/8","isCorrect":false},{"text":"192.168.0.0/24","isCorrect":false},{"text":"192.168.0.0/32","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of an AWS VPC Elastic IP address?","answers":[{"text":"To secure the communication between VPCs","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To enable IPv6 addressing for a VPC","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To provide a persistent public IP address for instances in a VPC","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To accelerate the delivery of content in a VPC","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which AWS service is used for domain registration and management in relation to AWS Route 53?","answers":[{"text":"Amazon EC2","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Amazon S3","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Amazon Route 53","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Amazon Registrar","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of an Amazon VPC peering connection?","answers":[{"text":"To connect a VPC to an on-premises data center","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To establish a dedicated physical link between two VPCs","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To enable communication between VPCs using private IP addresses","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To route traffic between VPCs using public IP addresses","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which AWS service provides a fully managed, highly available, and scalable domain name system (DNS) web service?","answers":[{"text":"Amazon VPC","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Amazon EC2","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Amazon Route 53","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Amazon S3","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of an Amazon VPC NAT Gateway?","answers":[{"text":"To route traffic between VPCs","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To encrypt VPC traffic","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To provide network address translation (NAT) for instances in a private subnet","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To establish a secure connection between VPCs","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which AWS service can be integrated with AWS VPC to provide a dedicated network connection between your on-premises data center and AWS?","answers":[{"text":"Amazon RDS","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Amazon S3","isCorrect":false},{"text":"AWS Direct Connect","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Amazon Route 53","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is an AWS VPC Flow Log?","answers":[{"text":"A log file generated by Amazon Route 53 for DNS queries","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A log file containing detailed information about traffic to and from network interfaces in a VPC","isCorrect":true},{"text":"A log file generated by Amazon VPC for routing updates","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A log file generated by AWS Lambda for function invocations","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you secure communication between a VPC and an on-premises data center?","answers":[{"text":"By using Amazon VPC peering connections","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By configuring VPC security groups","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By using an AWS Direct Connect connection","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By configuring VPC route tables","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is an Amazon VPC VPN Connection?","answers":[{"text":"A dedicated physical link between two VPCs","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A virtual private network (VPN) connection that extends your on-premises data center into the AWS Cloud","isCorrect":true},{"text":"A connection for routing traffic between VPCs using private IP addresses","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A connection for routing traffic between VPCs using public IP addresses","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of an AWS VPC Endpoint?","answers":[{"text":"To connect VPCs within the same AWS region","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To establish dedicated physical links between VPCs","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To provide private connectivity between VPC and supported AWS services without requiring an internet gateway","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To route traffic between VPCs using public IP addresses","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the maximum number of Elastic IP addresses you can allocate per AWS account by default?","answers":[{"text":"5","isCorrect":false},{"text":"10","isCorrect":false},{"text":"20","isCorrect":true},{"text":"50","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which AWS service is used for domain registration and management in relation to AWS Route 53?","answers":[{"text":"Amazon EC2","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Amazon S3","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Amazon Route 53","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Amazon Registrar","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of an Amazon VPC peering connection?","answers":[{"text":"To connect a VPC to an on-premises data center","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To establish a dedicated physical link between two VPCs","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To enable communication between VPCs using private IP addresses","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To route traffic between VPCs using public IP addresses","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which AWS service provides a fully managed, highly available, and scalable domain name system (DNS) web service?","answers":[{"text":"Amazon VPC","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Amazon EC2","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Amazon Route 53","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Amazon S3","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of an Amazon VPC NAT Gateway?","answers":[{"text":"To route traffic between VPCs","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To encrypt VPC traffic","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To provide network address translation (NAT) for instances in a private subnet","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To establish a secure connection between VPCs","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which AWS service can be integrated with AWS VPC to provide a dedicated network connection between your on-premises data center and AWS?","answers":[{"text":"Amazon RDS","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Amazon S3","isCorrect":false},{"text":"AWS Direct Connect","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Amazon Route 53","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is an AWS VPC Flow Log?","answers":[{"text":"A log file generated by Amazon Route 53 for DNS queries","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A log file containing detailed information about traffic to and from network interfaces in a VPC","isCorrect":true},{"text":"A log file generated by Amazon VPC for routing updates","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A log file generated by AWS Lambda for function invocations","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you secure communication between a VPC and an on-premises data center?","answers":[{"text":"By using Amazon VPC peering connections","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By configuring VPC security groups","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By using an AWS Direct Connect connection","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By configuring VPC route tables","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is an Amazon VPC VPN Connection?","answers":[{"text":"A dedicated physical link between two VPCs","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A virtual private network (VPN) connection that extends your on-premises data center to your VPC","isCorrect":true},{"text":"A direct connection between two VPCs without using the internet","isCorrect":false},{"text":"An encrypted connection between two Amazon EC2 instances","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of a VPC Peering Connection?","answers":[{"text":"To connect an on-premises data center to an Amazon VPC","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To establish a private, direct connection between VPCs","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To create a redundant VPC for high availability","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To connect Amazon S3 to an Amazon VPC","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which IP address range is reserved for the primary VPC CIDR block?","answers":[{"text":"10.0.0.0/8","isCorrect":true},{"text":"172.16.0.0/12","isCorrect":false},{"text":"192.168.0.0/16","isCorrect":false},{"text":"198.51.100.0/24","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How many Elastic IP addresses can be associated with an Amazon VPC instance by default?","answers":[{"text":"1","isCorrect":false},{"text":"5","isCorrect":false},{"text":"10","isCorrect":false},{"text":"None, Elastic IP addresses are not associated with VPC instances by default","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of a Network Access Control List (ACL) in Amazon VPC?","answers":[{"text":"To define security groups for EC2 instances","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To manage outbound traffic from Amazon VPC","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To control traffic to and from subnets within a VPC","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To define routing policies for VPC peering connections","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the key difference between a Network ACL (Access Control List) and a Security Group in Amazon VPC?","answers":[{"text":"Security Groups operate at the subnet level, while Network ACLs operate at the instance level","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Security Groups control inbound and outbound traffic, while Network ACLs control only inbound traffic","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Security Groups are stateful, while Network ACLs are stateless","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Security Groups operate at the instance level, while Network ACLs operate at the subnet level","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Which service is used to connect your on-premises data center to your Amazon VPC?","answers":[{"text":"AWS Direct Connect","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Amazon VPC Peering","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Amazon VPN Connection","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Amazon Route 53","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of a VPC Endpoint in Amazon VPC?","answers":[{"text":"To connect multiple VPCs within the same region","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To enable private communication between VPCs and supported AWS services","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To establish a dedicated connection between an EC2 instance and Amazon S3","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To create a redundant connection between an on-premises data center and an Amazon VPC","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the maximum number of Elastic IP addresses that can be allocated to your AWS account by default?","answers":[{"text":"5","isCorrect":false},{"text":"10","isCorrect":false},{"text":"20","isCorrect":false},{"text":"5 per region","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of the Default VPC in AWS?","answers":[{"text":"To provide a pre-configured VPC for development and testing purposes","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To serve as the primary VPC for all AWS accounts","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To establish a secure connection between AWS and on-premises data centers","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To create a dedicated VPC for high-performance computing workloads","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of a Bastion Host in Amazon VPC?","answers":[{"text":"To provide scalable compute capacity in a VPC","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To route traffic between VPCs","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To act as a secure gateway for accessing instances in a private subnet","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To serve as a load balancer for web applications","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which AWS service is used to manage DNS records in Amazon VPC?","answers":[{"text":"Amazon S3","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Amazon CloudFront","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Amazon Route 53","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Amazon RDS","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of Elastic Network Interfaces (ENIs) in Amazon VPC?","answers":[{"text":"To provide scalable storage for Amazon EC2 instances","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To enable communication between instances in different VPCs","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To attach multiple private IP addresses to an instance","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To establish a dedicated connection to an on-premises data center","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of the Default Security Group in Amazon VPC?","answers":[{"text":"To provide a pre-configured set of security rules for all instances in a VPC","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To establish a secure connection between VPCs","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To create a dedicated VPC for high-performance computing workloads","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To serve as a load balancer for web applications","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which VPC feature allows you to connect your VPC to the internet?","answers":[{"text":"Internet Gateway","isCorrect":true},{"text":"NAT Gateway","isCorrect":false},{"text":"VPC Peering","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Elastic Load Balancer","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of the Amazon VPC Flow Logs?","answers":[{"text":"To monitor traffic within an Amazon RDS instance","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To capture and log information about IP traffic going to and from network interfaces in your VPC","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To analyze the performance of Amazon EC2 instances","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To track changes to the VPC configuration","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the maximum number of VPCs that you can create in an AWS region by default?","answers":[{"text":"1","isCorrect":false},{"text":"5","isCorrect":false},{"text":"10","isCorrect":false},{"text":"VPC limits are soft limits and can be increased by contacting AWS support","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of a VPC Endpoint Service?","answers":[{"text":"To connect multiple VPCs within the same region","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To establish a dedicated connection between an EC2 instance and Amazon S3","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To enable private communication between VPCs and supported AWS services","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To create a redundant connection between an on-premises data center and an Amazon VPC","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of a VPC Security Group?","answers":[{"text":"To manage routing policies for VPCs","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To define access control policies for Amazon S3 buckets","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To control inbound and outbound traffic to instances in a VPC","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To establish a secure connection between VPCs","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which feature allows you to create a virtual network that closely resembles a traditional data center network in the cloud?","answers":[{"text":"VPC Peering","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Amazon VPC Flow Logs","isCorrect":false},{"text":"AWS Direct Connect","isCorrect":true},{"text":"VPC Endpoint","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of a VPC Endpoint for Amazon S3?","answers":[{"text":"To establish a dedicated connection between an EC2 instance and Amazon S3","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To enable private communication between VPCs and supported AWS services","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To allow instances in a VPC to connect to Amazon S3 without traversing the internet","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To create a redundant connection between an on-premises data center and an Amazon VPC","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which VPC feature allows you to connect one VPC to another VPC using private IP addresses?","answers":[{"text":"VPC Peering","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Internet Gateway","isCorrect":false},{"text":"NAT Gateway","isCorrect":false},{"text":"AWS Direct Connect","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of the Amazon VPC Route Table?","answers":[{"text":"To define access control policies for Amazon S3 buckets","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To manage routing policies for VPCs","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To establish a dedicated connection between an EC2 instance and Amazon S3","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To track changes to the VPC configuration","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which AWS service is used to create a dedicated connection from your on-premises data center to AWS?","answers":[{"text":"Amazon VPC Peering","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Amazon VPC Endpoint","isCorrect":false},{"text":"AWS Direct Connect","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Amazon Route 53","isCorrect":false}]}]')}}]);